<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ramblings on Rohit Goswami</title>
    <link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/ramblings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ramblings on Rohit Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 15:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/ramblings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Orgmode Note Workflow</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/org-note-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/org-note-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Background One of the main reasons to use orgmode is definitely to get a better note taking workflow. Closely related to blogging or writing, the ideal note workflow is one which lets you keep a bunch of throwaway ideas and also somehow have access to them in a coherent manner. This will be a long post, and it is a work-in-progress, so, keep that in mind. Since this is mainly me1 work-shopping my technique, the philosophy will come in a later post probably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Rationale</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 23:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rationale/</guid>
      <description> Why this site exists I have a lot of online presences. I have been around (or at-least, lurking) for over ten years. Almost as long as I have been programming. Anyway, I have a penchant lately for using emacs and honestly there isn&amp;rsquo;t very good support for org-mode files. There are options recently with gatsby as well, but this seemed kinda neat.
What &amp;lsquo;this&amp;rsquo; is  This site is built by Hugo The posts are generated with ox-hugo The theme is based of this excellent one by Djordje Atlialp, which in turn is based off of this theme by panr  My modifications are here   What is here  Mostly random thoughts I don&amp;rsquo;t mind people knowing Some tech stuff which isn&amp;rsquo;t coherent enough to be put in any form with references Emacs specific workflows which I might want to write about more than short notes on the config  What isn&amp;rsquo;t here  Some collections should and will go to my grimoire My doom-emacs configuration Academic stuff is better tracked on Publons or Google Scholar or my pages hosted by my favorite IITK group or UI group  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection of WebLinks</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rg-collection-weblinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/rg-collection-weblinks/</guid>
      <description>An attempt to re-claim and verify my digital presence.
 Background I mentioned on my about page, that it is nigh impossible to keep track of every digital trace there is of me. That said, it is really not even a countable infinite set yet, so it is a good idea to get started before it gets much worse. This is minimally curated, and will only be sporadically updated, so take everything here with a grain of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>