<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rohit Goswami</title>
    <link>https://rgoswami.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rohit Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 20:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring Dotfiles For Colemak</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-dots-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-dots-refactor/</guid>
      <description>Background I have, in the past written about how I made the switch to Colemak. However, until recently, I was still trying to mimic the VIM keybindings from QWERTY. This is a post where I discuss the changes I made to ensure that I never have to stretch my fingers in odd ways again. The main idea is expressed well by vim-colemak.
Colemak layout: | QWERTY layout: `12345 67890-= Move around: | (instead of) `12345 67890-= qwfpg jluy;[]\  e | k qwert yuiop[]\  arstd HNEIo&amp;#39; h i | h l asdfg HJKL;&amp;#39; zxcvb km,.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandoc to Orgmode with Babel</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/org-pandoc-babel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/org-pandoc-babel/</guid>
      <description>Background One of the best things about writing in orgmode is that we can embed and execute arbitrary code snippets. However, not all languages have an exporter, for obvious reasons. Somewhat surprisingly, there is no way to call pandoc on embedded snippets, which feels like a waste, especially when a whole bunch of documentation formats can be converted to orgmode with it.
Consider the following beautifully highlighted snippet of an rst (ReStructured Text) list table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Mathematica with Orgmode</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/org-mathematica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/org-mathematica/</guid>
      <description>Background I have been wanting to find a workflow which allows me to bypass writing a lot of TeX by hand for a while now. To that end I looked into using a computer algebra system (CAS). Naturally, my first choice was the FOSS Maxima (also because it uses Lisp under the hood). However, for all the reasons listed here, relating to its accuracy, which have not been fixed even though the post was over 5 years ago, I ended up having to go with the closed source Mathematica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS106A Small Group Training</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-trainig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-trainig/</guid>
      <description>Background As I mentioned earlier, I&amp;rsquo;m leading a section for Stanford CS106A: Code in Place. This post relates to the notes and thoughts garnered during the small group training session&amp;nbsp;1.
Reflections Demographics Redacted. Did not use breakout meetings due to privacy issues.
Engagement and Participation  Some people were more active (skewed responses) Some of the more rudimentary questions might have been suppressed  Highlighted Moments  Covering multiple perspectives Different mental models  Challenges and Transformations  Technical debt was an issue Lack of engagement Went on for too long  For me in particular:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS106A Section Meeting I</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-meet1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 22:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp-meet1/</guid>
      <description>Background As I mentioned earlier, I&amp;rsquo;m leading a section for Stanford CS106A: Code in Place. I did also mention I&amp;rsquo;d try to keep a set of short notes on the process. I finally had my first section meeting!
Preparation I went through the following:
 Sent out a welcome message Detailed the workflow Set up a HackMD instance Set up some slides in beamer&amp;nbsp;1  However, after that, I was still concerned since I didn&amp;rsquo;t get much of a response on the ice-breakers for EdStem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Section On-boarding</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 02:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-smallgrp/</guid>
      <description>Background As I mentioned in my last post, I&amp;rsquo;m leading a section for Stanford CS106A: Code in Place. I did also mention I&amp;rsquo;d try to keep a set of short notes on the process. So there1.
The Training Given the overwhelming number of students, and section leaders, the small groups are for fostering a community of teachers.
Consider allowing for daisy chaining during introductions Discussions are the primary take-away Only the instructor should be coding during the session  Core components  Clarity Content Atmosphere Section management Correctness  Sectional Details  Check in at the start Notice the space Check in regularly Avoid negative phrases Establish norms and the general culture  Zoom Norms  Have people introduce themselves Mute people when they aren&amp;rsquo;t talking Raise hands Try to use icebreakers which respect privacy  Materials Here&amp;rsquo;s some of the stuff which, being as it was open-sourced, I suppose is OK to put here2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-boarding for Code in Place</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</guid>
      <description>Background A few weeks ago, I ended up recording a video for the Stanford CS106A: Code in Place initiative (which can be found here). I heard back a while ago, and am now to lead a section for the course!
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be making a series of short posts as this process continues.
On-Boarding This was very reminiscent of the Carpentries instructor training, which makes sense, given how well thought out that experience was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Google to Goat</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-google/</guid>
      <description>Background Like a lot of my tech based rants, this was brought on by a recent Hacker News post. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into why the product listed there is a hollow faux FOSS rip-off. I won&amp;rsquo;t discuss how that &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; analytics option, like many others are just hobby projects taking pot shots at other projects. Or how insanely overpriced most alternatives are.
I will however discuss why and how I transitioned to using the awesome Goat Counter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trees and Bags</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/trees-and-bags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/trees-and-bags/</guid>
      <description>Explain why using bagging for prediction trees generally improves predictions over regular prediction trees.
 Introduction Bagging (or Bootstrap Aggregation) is one of the most commonly used ensemble method for improving the prediction of trees. We will broadly follow a historical development trend to understand the process. That is, we will begin by considering the Bootstrap method. This in turn requires knowledge of the Jacknife method, which is understandable from a simple bias variance perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone Should Get an A - David MacKay</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 02:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</guid>
      <description>Background  I recently read this post written by the now deceased Prof. David MacKay&amp;nbsp;1 It should be read widely, however, given that it is distributed as a ps.gz which is then a .ps file, and thus probably inaccessible to many of the people who should read it, I decided to rework it for native online consumption (there is also a pdf) THIS IS NOT MY CONTENT&amp;nbsp;2 Now, enjoy the post  Everyone Should Get an A Imagine a University – call it Camwick – where all students arrive with straight A grades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>