<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Rohit Goswami</title>
    <link>https://rgoswami.me/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Rohit Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 20:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring Dotfiles For Colemak</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-dots-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-dots-refactor/</guid>
      <description>Background I have, in the past written about how I made the switch to Colemak. However, until recently, I was still trying to mimic the VIM keybindings from QWERTY. This is a post where I discuss the changes I made to ensure that I never have to stretch my fingers in odd ways again. The main idea is expressed well by vim-colemak.
Colemak layout: | QWERTY layout: `12345 67890-= Move around: | (instead of) `12345 67890-= qwfpg jluy;[]\  e | k qwert yuiop[]\  arstd HNEIo&amp;#39; h i | h l asdfg HJKL;&amp;#39; zxcvb km,.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning Dotfiles on an HPC</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/prov-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/prov-dots/</guid>
      <description>Background My dotfiles turned 4 years old a few months ago (since 9th Jan 2017) and remains one of my most frequently updated projects for obvious reasons. Going through the changes reminds me of a whole of posts I never got around to writing.
Anyway, recently I gained access to another HPC cluster, with a standard configuration (bash, old CentOS) and decided to track my provisioning steps. This is really a very streamlined experience by now, since I&amp;rsquo;ve used the same setup across scores of machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Colemak</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</guid>
      <description>Background I just realized that it has been over two years since I switched from QWERTY to COLEMAK but somehow never managed to write about it. It was a major change in my life, and it took forever to get acclimatized to. I do not think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever again be in a position to make such a change in my life again, but it was definitely worth it.
Touch Typing My interest in touch typing in I decided to digitize my notes for posterity, during the last two years of my undergraduate studies back in Harcourt Butler Technical Institute (HBTI) Kanpur, India.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>