<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Rohit Goswami</title>
    <link>https://rgoswami.me/categories/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Rohit Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/categories/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>D3 for Git</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</guid>
      <description>Background  I have had a lot of discussions regarding the teaching of git This is mostly as a part of the SoftwareCarpentries, or in view of my involvement with univ.ai, or simply in every public space I am associated with Without getting into my views, I just wanted to keep this resource in mind  The site  Learning git is a highly contentious thing People seem to be fond of GUI tools, especially since on non *nix systems, it seems that there is a lot of debate surrounding obtaining the git utility in the first place  One of the best ways of understanding (without installing stuff) the mental models required for working with git is this site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Colemak</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</guid>
      <description>Background I just realized that it has been over two years since I switched from QWERTY to COLEMAK but somehow never managed to write about it. It was a major change in my life, and it took forever to get acclimatized to. I do not think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever again be in a position to make such a change in my life again, but it was definitely worth it.
Touch Typing My interest in touch typing in I decided to digitize my notes for posterity, during the last two years of my undergraduate studies back in Harcourt Butler Technical Institute (HBTI) Kanpur, India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming Github Notifications</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/ghnotif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 11:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/ghnotif/</guid>
      <description>Background As a member of several large organizations, I get a lot of github notifications. Not all of these are of relevance to me. This is especially true of psuedo-monorepo style repositories like the JOSS review system and especially the exercism community.
 I recently (re-)joined the exercism community as a maintainer for the C++ lessons after having been a (sporadic) teacher This was largely in response to a community call to action as the group needed new blood to usher in v3 of the exercism project  Anyway, I have since found that at the small cost of possibly much of my public repo data, I can manage my notifications better with Octobox</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>