<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rohit Goswami</title>
    <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rohit Goswami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rgoswami.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On-boarding for Code in Place</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/scp-onboarding/</guid>
      <description>Background A few weeks ago, I ended up recording a video for the Stanford CS106A: Code in Place initiative (which can be found here). I heard back a while ago, and am now to lead a section for the course!
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be making a series of short posts as this process continues.
On-Boarding This was very reminiscent of the Carpentries instructor training, which makes sense, given how well thought out that experience was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Google to Goat</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/goat-google/</guid>
      <description>Background Like a lot of my tech based rants, this was brought on by a recent Hacker News post. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into why the product listed there is a hollow faux FOSS rip-off. I won&amp;rsquo;t discuss how that &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; analytics option, like many others are just hobby projects taking pot shots at other projects. Or how insanely overpriced most alternatives are.
I will however discuss why and how I transitioned to using the awesome Goat Counter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trees and Bags</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/trees-and-bags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/trees-and-bags/</guid>
      <description>Explain why using bagging for prediction trees generally improves predictions over regular prediction trees.
 Introduction Bagging (or Bootstrap Aggregation) is one of the most commonly used ensemble method for improving the prediction of trees. We will broadly follow a historical development trend to understand the process. That is, we will begin by considering the Bootstrap method. This in turn requires knowledge of the Jacknife method, which is understandable from a simple bias variance perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone Should Get an A - David MacKay</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 02:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/mackay-all-a/</guid>
      <description>Background  I recently read this post written by the now deceased Prof. David MacKay&amp;nbsp;1 It should be read widely, however, given that it is distributed as a ps.gz which is then a .ps file, and thus probably inaccessible to many of the people who should read it, I decided to rework it for native online consumption (there is also a pdf) THIS IS NOT MY CONTENT&amp;nbsp;2 Now, enjoy the post  Everyone Should Get an A Imagine a University – call it Camwick – where all students arrive with straight A grades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3 for Git</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/d3git/</guid>
      <description>Background  I have had a lot of discussions regarding the teaching of git This is mostly as a part of the SoftwareCarpentries, or in view of my involvement with univ.ai, or simply in every public space I am associated with Without getting into my views, I just wanted to keep this resource in mind  The site  Learning git is a highly contentious thing People seem to be fond of GUI tools, especially since on non *nix systems, it seems that there is a lot of debate surrounding obtaining the git utility in the first place  One of the best ways of understanding (without installing stuff) the mental models required for working with git is this site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shorter Posts</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/shortpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/shortpost/</guid>
      <description> Background Sometime this year, I realized that I no longer have access to a lot of my older communication. This included, a lot of resources I enjoyed and shared with the people who were around me at that point in time. To counter this, I have decided to opt for shorter posts, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t always include the same level of detail I would prefer to provide.
Alternatives  I have an automated system based around IFTTT combined with Twitter, Diigo, and even Pocket However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really tell me much, and trawling through a massive glut of data is often pointless as well There&amp;rsquo;s always Twitter, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really care to hear the views of others when I want to revisit my own ideas  Conclusions  I will be making shorter posts here, like the random one on octobox  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning Dotfiles on an HPC</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/prov-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/prov-dots/</guid>
      <description>Background My dotfiles turned 4 years old a few months ago (since 9th Jan 2017) and remains one of my most frequently updated projects for obvious reasons. Going through the changes reminds me of a whole of posts I never got around to writing.
Anyway, recently I gained access to another HPC cluster, with a standard configuration (bash, old CentOS) and decided to track my provisioning steps. This is really a very streamlined experience by now, since I&amp;rsquo;ve used the same setup across scores of machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Colemak</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/colemak-switch/</guid>
      <description>Background I just realized that it has been over two years since I switched from QWERTY to COLEMAK but somehow never managed to write about it. It was a major change in my life, and it took forever to get acclimatized to. I do not think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever again be in a position to make such a change in my life again, but it was definitely worth it.
Touch Typing My interest in touch typing in I decided to digitize my notes for posterity, during the last two years of my undergraduate studies back in Harcourt Butler Technical Institute (HBTI) Kanpur, India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bojack Horseman</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/bojack-horseman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/bojack-horseman/</guid>
      <description>Background For a while I was worried about writing about a TV show here. I thought it might be frivolous, or worse, might outweigh the other kinds of articles I would like to write. However, like most things, that which is ignored just grows, so it is easier to just write and forget about it.
The Show Much has been said about how Bojack Horseman is one of the best shows ever, and they&amp;rsquo;re all correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISLR :: Moving Beyond Linearity</title>
      <link>https://rgoswami.me/posts/islr-ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 09:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rgoswami.me/posts/islr-ch7/</guid>
      <description>Chapter VII - Moving Beyond Linearity All the questions are as per the ISL seventh printing.
Common libsUsed&amp;lt;-c(&amp;#34;dplyr&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;ggplot2&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;tidyverse&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;ISLR&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;caret&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;MASS&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;gridExtra&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;pls&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;latex2exp&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;data.table&amp;#34;) invisible(lapply(libsUsed, library, character.only = TRUE))## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39;## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;: ## ## filter, lag## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, union## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.3.0 ──## ✔ tibble 2.1.3 ✔ purrr 0.3.3 ## ✔ tidyr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>